<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>

<document>

  <properties>
    <title>FAQ - Frequently Asked Questions</title>
    <author email="netseeker@manskes.de">Michael Manske</author>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <section name="FAQ - Frequently Asked Questions">
      <p>
        Please read this carefully before posting in the issue tracker
      </p>
      <a name="demon"/>
      <subsection name="How can I install InfoQuiver as system demon?">
        <p>
            Take a look at the &quot;<a href="http://wrapper.tanukisoftware.org/">Java Service Wrapper</a>&quot;. It provides the neccessary
            features to run InfoQuiver as a Windows Service or Unix Daemon.
        </p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="How can i avoid OutOfMemoryExceptions?">
        <p>
            Edit InfoQuivers start script (InfoQuiver.bat|InfoQuiver.sh) and increase the value for
            the max. used memory:
            <p>
                <code>java -mx256m -cp %CC_CLASSPATH% net.sf.iquiver.DefaultIQuiverStarter</code>
            </p>
        </p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="Does the POP3Transport include support for spam filtering?">
        <p>
            No, InfoQuiver doesn't include support for spam filtering itself. However you can use
            a spam filter which includes a "POP3 Proxy", eg. <a href="http://spambayes.sourceforge.net/">SpamBayes</a>.
            Such a proxy acts as local POP3 client + server, so you have to set up the proxy as client for the
            targeted POP3 inbox and then configure the POP3 transport attributes in InfoQuiver to use "localhost" as POP3 Server.
        </p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="I would like to use format xyz, but InfoQuiver doesn't provide a adequate parser. What can i do?">
        <p>
            In such a case there are two options:
            <ol>
                <li>Write your own parser, see <a href="extend/index.html">the extension guide</a></li>
                <li>If there exists an application which is able to parse format xyz and output the result 
                    to your systems standard output, you can use InfoQuivers DelegateParser to invoke that application,
                    all you need to do is to add an content type for your information source, set up DelegateParser as parser
                    for this content type and insert the command used for invoking the external application in the "Parser arguments"
                    field.                    
                </li>
            </ol>
        </p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="I would like to use protocoll xyz to fetch a content source, but InfoQuiver doesn't provide a adequate transport. What can i do?">
        <p>
            <ol>
                <li>You could write your own transport, see <a href="extend/index.html">the extension guide</a></li>
                <li>If there exists an application which is able to fetch information via protocol xyz and output the result 
                    to your systems standard output, you can use InfoQuivers DelegateTransport to invoke that application.<br/>
                    If the application can output the content only to the filesystem you could schedule the application outside of
                    InfoQuiver, eg. via cron or at task, and use InfoQuivers FSTransport to get the contents into InfoQuiver.
                </li>
            </ol>
        </p>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
