<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Front Page</title>
    <author email="netseeker@manskes.de">Michael Manske</author>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <section name="InfoQuiver">
        <p> InfoQuiver will be a server demon, which supports automatic querying and indexing of many kinds of 
            information datasources. It will include build-in support for most diverse information formats and 
            protocols as well as report generation and -dispatching. InfoQuiver fetches content from defined content 
            sources, stores it in its metaformat in a database, adds the content per client to a lucene full-text search
            index and will run user defined searches on the stored and indexed content.</p>
        <p> Searchresults will be produced in the form of customizable reports and dispatched for each user, usergroup
            or client.</p>
        <p> Most of usual transports (HTTP and HTTPS, FTP and SFTP, WEBDAV, SOAP and XML-RPC, POP, IMAP, SMPT,
            local file system, CIFS...) and formats (HTML, RSS, PDF as well as various open XML dialects and office formats)
            are discussed to become medium-term to support.</p>
        <p> InfoQuiver runs on a lot of plattforms as well as with nearly every common database system.
            It uses <a href="http://db.apache.org/torque">Torque</a> as persistence layer with a simplified and 
            powerful, <a 
            href="http://www.manskes.de/cms/front_content.php?idart=71&amp;idcat=32&amp;idcatart=&amp;lang=1">cluster 
            aware caching solution.</a> Full-text search is build on top of <a href="http://jakarta.apache.org/lucene/">Jakarta Lucene</a>
            supplemented with extensions for:
            <ul>
                <li>pdf documents (build on top of <a href="http://www.pdfbox.org/">PDFBox</a>)</li>
                <li>MS Word .doc documents</li>
                <li>MS Excel .xls documents</li>
                <li>rss, opml and atom feeds (thanks to <a href="http://informa.sourceforge.net/">Informa</a>)</li>
                <li>raw xml documents</li>
                <li>binary data as well as multipart/mixed</li>
            </ul>
        </p>
        <p>As for the moment InfoQuiver is in an early development stage even if the core services do already 
           work very well.</p>
        <p><br/></p>
        <p align="center">
            <a href="http://maven.apache.org/"><img src="images/maven.jpg" border="0" height="35" width="133" alt="Built with Maven"/></a>
            <a href="http://jakarta.apache.org/ant/"><img src="images/ant_logo_small.gif" border="0" hspace="20" alt="Powered by Ant"/></a>
            <a href="http://jakarta.apache.org/lucene/"><img src="images/lucene_green_150.gif" alt="Powered by Lucene"/></a>
            <a href="http://jasperreports.sourceforge.net/"><img src="images/jasperreports.png" hspace="20" alt="Powered by JasperReports"/></a>
            <a href="http://www.mysql.com/"><img src="images/mysql.gif" border="0" alt="Works with MySQL"/></a>                        
        </p>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>    